Time for your big debut.
出道戰總算開始了
Vice-Captain Hoshina, I've located the Yoju core.
保科副隊長，我知道餘獸的核心在哪裡了
What?
-什麼？ -是在頸根部
And there's one more thing. This one's important.
還有一件事，這點很重要
The Yoju have reproductive organs too.
餘獸也有增殖器官
If we don't destroy those organs, their corpses might spawn new Yoju.
不破壞的話 餘獸屍體可能會生出新的餘獸
Target sighted.
鎖定目標
No additional targets in area.
周邊無狙擊的威脅對象
Roger. You are cleared to fire.
瞭解，開始射擊
Fire.
射擊
Watch this one closely, Kafka.
卡夫卡，看仔細了
That's the power of the person you're trying to stand beside.
這就是你希望能與其並肩作戰之人的力量
Honju has taken critical damage and has stopped moving entirely.
擊破主獸，已完全停止活動
Just like I thought.
果然如事前所料
We killed the Honju, but the Yoju are still alive inside its corpse...
就算打倒主獸，屍體裡還有殘留的餘獸
and are going to come swarming out.
最後會傾巢而出
Hey, you didn't hear the alarm?
喂，你沒聽到警報嗎？
The cleanup crew won't be needed until later.
現在還沒輪到解體業者出場
Aw, this one's no good either.
這傢伙也一樣
The reproductive organs I loaded them with have been destroyed.
事先放入的增殖器官被破壞了
Maybe there's somebody on the force who knows all about Kaiju?
隊員裡有人很瞭解怪獸嗎？
EPISODE 7: KAIJU NO. 9
（第7集：怪獸9號）
Wow, the Honju's huge!
主獸好大隻啊
Find Kafka and Ichikawa?
你有看到卡夫卡跟市川嗎？
You know we can't see them from up here.
看得到才有鬼咧
I can see why they called every cleanup company in Tokyo and Kanagawa.
這也難怪他們要召集 東京和神奈川的所有解體業者
Hey, did you see the new guy?
喂，你們有看到新人嗎？
You don't think he's locked himself in the bathroom again?
八成又跑去蹲廁所了吧？
Want me to go get him?
要我去叫他過來嗎？
Thanks.
拜託你了
Hey, look.
你聽我說
This place is still dangerous.
這裡還很危險
Stay out of here until we give the all clear.
在收到指示前，你就乖乖待命
Move, Iharu-kun!
伊春，快閃開！
Oh, I missed your heart, huh?
我沒打中心臟啊
I guess I'm not as accurate in this form.
這個身體型態真是會影響準確度啊
Iharu-kun!
伊春！
The bleeding won't stop!
血流不止，可惡
Calm down and use your suit to stop the bleeding!
你冷靜點，先進行止血操作
Who the hell are you?
你這傢伙是何方神聖？
A Kaiju?
怪獸？
The only humanoid Kaiju I know that's not Senpai is...
除了前輩以外的人形怪獸，那就只有…
the one from the exam!
在測驗會場出現的人形怪獸
This is the one that took down Shinomiya?
這就是擊傷四之宮的那個傢伙嗎？
I think so.
應該沒錯
Well, I don't want to just return empty-handed.
就這樣撤退好像也不太爽
Maybe I can at least take home a live sample of a Defense Force officer.
至少帶幾個隊員的活體樣本回去好了
Platoon Leader Ikaruga, we've encountered a humanoid Kaiju.
斑鳩小隊長，我們遇見人形怪獸了
Send backup immediately!
請立即派人支援
Platoon Leader!
小隊長？
No...
怎麼會？
Oh, right. Your communicator thingies.
對了，你們的通訊系統啊
I've figured those out.
早就被我破解了
This area is completely undetectable from the outside world.
這個區域已經陷入 外部無法偵測的空間之中
I came up with this trick to help me stay hidden among humans,
這原本是我用來藏身人類世界的技倆
but it works well for hunting humans too, you know.
沒想到也能用來狩獵呢
Reno!
雷諾！
Huh? I'm not quite hitting my targets.
奇怪？好像都會有點射偏耶
He's breaking right through my suit's shields.
牠能輕而易舉地突破戰鬥服的防護
But...
可是…
Oh, I get it. You see it, don't you?
你看得見，對吧？
Oh, right.
對了
Let me tell you this just in case you ever run into him.
我先告訴你們一件事 以防你們遇到那個傢伙
At first it looks like he's using some kind of magic or something,
乍看之下也許很像魔術或妖術
but watch his fingers closely.
但是仔細觀察牠的指尖
You'll see him prepare for the attack.
就會發現牠有個特定的預備動作
I can dodge them!
我躲得過
He dodged it!
他躲掉了
So I was right.
果然沒錯啊
Get out of here and call for backup.
伊春，你快逃離這裡去求援
Why do I have to let you protect me?
為什麼搞得好像我需要你來保護？
Iharu-kun!
伊春
Go, please.
請你快走
I'm scared.
好可怕
Even Shinomiya didn't stand a chance against him,
連四之宮都打不過的對手
so I sure as hell don't.
我怎麼可能有勝算？
But...
可是
The Defense Force officer I want to be...
我想成為的防衛隊員…
Ichikawa, run!
市川，你快逃
Once you're sure you're safe, call it in!
到了安全的地方再通報防衛隊
...is a man who would put his life on the line for his buddies like this!
…是能在這種情況下 挺身保護隊友的男人
I can at least buy enough time for Iharu-kun to get out of here!
至少要爭取時間讓伊春逃跑
Reno's a totally different guy than he was yesterday!
雷諾已經不可同日而語了
What happened to him?
到底是怎麼回事？
How can he fight that thing?
為什麼他有辦法跟那種怪獸戰鬥？
Damn it! Damn it all!
可惡！可惡啊！
I hate this! I hate it!
讓人好不爽！有夠不爽啊！
You'll hit a wall unleashing your combat power.
大家會在解放戰力上遇到一個瓶頸
Usually around 20% to 30%.
大約會在20%至30%時出現
Only a very few people can scale that wall,
只有少數人能突破這個瓶頸
but everyone has the potential within them to do it.
不過，每個人都具有突破瓶頸的潛力
I've been stuck at 20% for almost two weeks.
我已經停滯在20%快兩週了
Ever since that day, I've thought of nothing but getting stronger.
從那天起，我就一心只想著要變強
But he...
但是…
He surpassed me like it was nothing!
他輕易地就超越了我
And I hate it!
讓人有夠不爽！
You seem to know a few things about me.
你似乎事先掌握了我的情報
But you don't know about this one, do you?
但這個你應該就不知道了吧？
Huh?
喔？
Iharu-kun? Why?
伊春？為什麼？
It's me... the guy who hasn't changed a bit since that day.
而是從那天之後就毫無長進
The guy who always needs somebody else to save him!
只能受到別人保護的自己
Listen, Reno. You ain't saving me.
你聽好，雷諾，不是由你來保護我
I'm saving you, dumbass.
而是由我來保護你，蠢蛋
Iharu-kun.
伊春
Not sure what I'm seeing here.
無法理解
Didn't you go to get help?
你不是去搬救兵了嗎？
Shut up!
少囉嗦
If I hadn't come back, you'd be dead right now!
要是我沒回來，你早就被幹掉了吧
Oh, you were trying to get him out of here?
原來你是想讓他逃命啊
That won't work.
沒用的
Nothing, living or otherwise,
不管是物品或生物
can leave this space without my permission.
沒有我的許可就無法離開這裡
You heard the guy.
你聽見了吧
Gotta fight, then.
我們只能豁出去了
Let's take him down together, Reno!
一起打倒這傢伙吧，雷諾！
I ain't doing so good, though.
不過我這個樣子
I'll back you up, get you an opening.
我只能掩護你，幫你製造機會
So hit him as hard as you can!
你就使出全力，一擊把牠打爆
Right!
好
Let's go, Reno!
上吧，雷諾！
A conductor round?
雷擊彈？
You aren't the only one who's trying all the different bullets!
你以為只有你會嘗試不同彈藥嗎？
This stuff makes it hard to move.
這樣會妨礙我的行動
Guess I'll stop him first.
我先解決他好了
Focus.
仔細觀察
You've already taken a hit from him once. You know how the timing works!
我被牠擊中過一次，應該懂得掌握時機了
Him too, huh?
這個也可以嗎？
Now, Reno!
雷諾，趁現在！
Unleash maximum combat power!
解放最大戰力
Please, God... just this once... just this one moment...
神啊，我只求現在就好，請祢在這個瞬間
Give me more power
賜給我
than Shinomiya or Captain Ashiro!
比四之宮和亞白隊長還強大的力量
What the hell?
什麼？
A wall of corpses?
堆積如牆的屍體？
From the look of it...
看樣子
I guess you're screwed, huh?
你已經無計可施了吧？
Reno!
雷諾！
Vice-Captain Hoshina, this is Platoon Leader Ikaruga.
保科副隊長，這裡是斑鳩小隊
What's up?
怎麼了？
We've lost contact with Ichikawa and Furuhashi.
我們從剛剛就聯絡不上市川和古橋
What?
什麼？
We've lost communication and vitals signals.
完全偵測不到兩人的通訊及生命徵象
Ichikawa?
市川？
Did I just see that thing move?
剛才牠是不是動了一下？
Kafka Hibino!
日比野卡夫卡
Kikoru! Does this mean...?
琪歌露，這個反應是…
Yeah.
沒錯
He's here.
那傢伙來了
Ichikawa... Iharu!
市川跟伊春…
Reno!
雷諾！
My whole body is burning...
身體好燙
I need to have the suit stop the bleeding and stand up.
我得進行止血，然後站起來
I'm still alive!
我還活著
The battle's not over!
戰鬥還沒結束
You can still move, huh?
你還動得了啊
It's surprisingly hard to halt a human's motor functions
要消除身體功能而沒消滅生命
without killing them.
沒想到還滿困難的嘛
No you don't!
你休想得逞
I've seen that trick already.
這招我已經看慣了
Now, time to wrap this up.
好了，差不多該來解決這邊了
Would this be too weak?
這樣一擊會太弱嗎？
Damn it...
可惡…
You can still move, huh?
還動得了啊
-Damn it! -Well, how about this?
-可惡！ -這樣如何呢？
My comrade's getting hurt right in front of me
隊友在我面前受盡折磨
and I can't do a thing to stop it?
我卻無能為力
I hate it...
好不甘心
I hate to admit it...
雖然我不想承認
But Reno is incredible!
但雷諾真的很不得了
He'll become a captain someday!
總有一天他一定會當上隊長
I won't let it end for him here!
我才不會讓他死在這裡！
I'm about done with him, so I don't need you anymore.
我已經處理好這邊了，所以不需要你了
Please, God...
神啊，求求祢
Or a demon or the devil himself... I don't care.
不對，就算是魔鬼或惡魔也好
Save Reno...
請救救雷諾
Save my friend!
救救我的夥伴
Go ahead and die now.
受死吧
The only one dying here is you, asshole.
該受死的是你，混蛋
What just happened?
發生什麼事了？
I can see my own torso...?
我怎麼會看到自己的軀體？
Oh, my head got knocked off!
啊，我的頭被打飛了嗎？
Sorry I'm late.
抱歉，我來晚了
I'm so weak...
我好弱啊
I wanted so bad... to stop this from happening.
還自以為能夠避免演變成這種局面
But in the end...
結果還是…
I made him transform one more time.
又讓他變身了
A-Another humanoid-type?
另一隻人形怪獸？
Oh, so that's you, huh?
啊，就是你吧
You're...
傳聞中的…
Kaiju No. 8.
怪獸8號
Sorry, Ichikawa. Looks like it's gonna take a little longer.
抱歉啊，市川，看來還需要一點時間
No...
前…
It'll be fine.
沒事的
Just calm down. Have the suit close the wounds one by one.
你冷靜地慢慢進行止血操作
I guess you don't need a lecture from me on that, huh?
話說這也輪不到我來教吧？
I can't even do it.
我自己又辦不到
Senpai...
前輩
Be careful.
你小心點
Yeah.
嗯
Just let me handle this.
交給我吧
I know he's strong,
我知道前輩很強大
but I've got a bad feeling...
但我有種不祥的預感
Not that I'm mad or anything,
我是無所謂啦
but why are you getting in my way when you're a Kaiju, too?
可是你明明是怪獸，為什麼要來妨礙我？
And also, you're a lot stronger than I thought you were.
而且你這個怪獸遠比我想得還要強大呢
I'd like to have your corpse so I can use it.
好想收下你的屍體來當手下啊
He managed to hurt Senpai in his Kaiju form?
牠竟然能打傷變身為怪獸的前輩？
I see. You're tough. If I'm gonna kill you...
原來如此，你很堅固嘛，如果要幹掉你…
I'm probably gonna need about this much.
大概需要這樣的力量才行吧
He wasn't taking the fight with us seriously at all?!
這傢伙對付我們的時候，根本沒使出全力
Senpai, run!
前輩，快跑…
Oh...
原來如此
So this is the stuff you've been shooting them with
你就是在他們身上使出這種攻擊
over and over again?
把他們打得傷痕累累的啊
Huh?
咦？
What?
什麼？
The wall of corpses?
屍體堆成的牆壁？
I'll heal while I have the chance...
讓我趁機修復…
What?
什麼？
What is this guy?
這傢伙是怎麼回事？
Protect.
進行防護
Can't take... direct hit...
躲開直接攻擊
He's pushing me back?
我被他壓著打？
Abnormal.
異常
Something's wrong.
好像不太對勁
The damage I've taken is taking too long to repair.
受損部位修復得好慢
Confusion.
混亂
Temporary retreat.
暫時撤退
No opportunity to retreat.
找不到撤退時機
Your core's in your torso, right?
你的核心就在軀體裡吧
Brace yourself, 'cause I'm about to punch a hole in it!
咬緊牙關吧，看我怎麼打爆你！
Oh, this is bad.
這下不妙了
Oh no. My core is completely exposed.
核心完全暴露在外了
It's over.
你完蛋了
Th-This is Ikaruga Platoon! We've discovered a humanoid Kaiju!
這裡是斑鳩小隊，發現人形怪獸
It's not strong enough!
威力不夠
How far did he go?
那傢伙到底去哪裡了？
You're going to find Reno and Iharu?
你要去找雷諾跟伊春？
Their communications are offline, and we can't even detect their vitals!
通訊失聯又偵測不到生命徵象
How?
你要怎麼找？
If they're with that other humanoid...
如果他們跟那隻人形怪獸在一起…
I should be able to sense him.
我應該有辦法感測到
Kikoru.
琪歌露
Take care of things while I'm gone!
這裡就交給你了
Wait!
等一下！
He transformed right here?
他竟然在這種地方變身
This is Ikaruga Platoon!
這是斑鳩小隊
We've discovered a humanoid Kaiju in the southeast of Sector Foxtrot,
在F地區東南區域發現人形怪獸
It matches the description of Kaiju No. 8!
根據特徵來看，應該是怪獸8號
Roger.
瞭解
Sending a neutralization unit now.
我馬上派出討伐部隊
That idiot...
那個白痴
The mimetic space was destroyed, huh?
擬態空間壞了嗎？
But that gave me the opportunity I needed.
但也多虧如此，才讓我有機可乘
Crap!
糟了
I now understand how you work.
我已經掌握了你的特性
Next time, I can kill you.
下次我就可以幹掉你了
I won't let you go!
你休想逃跑
You behave like a human, even though you're a Kaiju.
你明明是隻怪獸，行為卻像人類
We'll meet again, Kaiju No. 8.
我們下次再見了，怪獸8號
Damn it! I've got no choice but to get out of here myself!
可惡，沒辦法，我也得撤了
He got away!
被牠逃跑了
Help the wounded!
快救助傷者
Good.
太好了
I let the humanoid-type get away, but I did what I set out to do.
雖然被人形怪獸逃走，但至少達成目的了
A coal-black body and a skull face, like a demon.
漆黑的身體以及鬼怪般的骷髏長相
I've finally found you, Kaiju No. 8.
終於逮到你了，怪獸8號
Ho...
保…
Vice-Captain Hoshina!
保科副隊長
This is Hoshina.
我是保科
I've made contact with Kaiju No. 8 in Sector Foxtrot.
在F地區與怪獸8號接觸
Looks like you've been having some fun with my men.
我們的隊員承蒙你照顧了
No, Vice-Captain Hoshina...
不對，保科副隊長
That person is...
那個人是…
But when it comes to the smaller and mid-sized enemies,
對付小型和中型怪獸
I think I'm a bit better than she is.
我應該略勝她一籌
He wasn't bluffing!
他不是在虛張聲勢
He's got a lot of experience fighting smaller Kaiju!
他很擅於對付小型怪獸
Well, you're a tough one.
皮真厚啊
I'm pretty sure I landed at least a few hits.
我應該有砍中兩、三刀啊
I've only ever seen him with that grin on his face.
我只看過他一臉笑瞇瞇的樣子
But this is...
但這就是…
Time to stop messing around, then.
我得拿出真本事了
This is what Vice-Captain Hoshina looks like when he's killing Kaiju!
…撲殺怪獸時的保科副隊長
Requesting permission to remove limiter.
請求解除限制
Roger!
瞭解
I'll be the one to...
怪獸8號就由我來…
Unleashed combat power, 92%!
解放戰力92%
...neutralize No. 8.
討伐